Hi, I'm...learn I'm a senior program manager
...the operating systems group here at microsoft and today
we'll be talking about cross platform localization with the multi-lingual apt toolkit.
...about toolkit has been available since windows eight timeframe but recently we've
...it to support the visual studio plus the salmon project support
so-if you have zimmer projects ios android or the news
...form will just work with that environment inside visual studio plus
The toolkit provides...a developer is easy access to many
markets for example, if you want to get into any market like germany
...china you need to do...globalization that
can be a real pain so what we do is we allow you to focus on your features of your
app rather than your languages so just programming your source language all be
...in english as...example but it can be any source language you want that will allow you
with the toolkit to migrate easily into other
languages we provide a seamless workflow censure inside visual studio with
...project it just works as if it was a visual studio windows project so that if you
...one the work for works across-the-board regardless of
you target platform are we the instant access to translation services,
for example, microsoft translator is a pay for service
with the toolkit we give use access to that service without charge we also
hook you up with microsoft professionally translated strings from our products such as
microsoft office microsoft windows etc and,
we enable both by friends and family and community level support so-if you want-to go higher
...recycle or machine translation quality
that's very easy to do with your friends family or professional translation houses.
So, let's go ahead and jump in what I have is I have three demos we're going
to run today and they're all from the...get website so these are all readily available
to download and I've download...I've had to do a little bit of tuning for localization but
craig done has some great videos on how to localized...forms which is the example
organ use here so, I'm not going to go deep into that I'm going to show how the toolkit works if
your application is localize...so let's jump right into visual studio.
So, here we have visual studio two thousand thirteen with those...project
...this is the tab demo patched tab page demo from
zimmerman written by charles...they actually demonstrated at...and twenty fourteen
event so I've taken the program and I've actually modified to be localized locus it was hard
...strings which is usually how programs are
...I would recommend...will...even if
...english but I'm not going to get into how I made that localization and
...communicated with craig done and he's the localization...
and he does...and demos on it if you look him up on code ...get hub you'll find his
to do localization app and that's a great way to learn how he does localization inside the forms
what's keaton although is in the application we have our resources in
our res xfiles so I'm...go ahead and just run this.
And, we're going to see how this works on ios machine I've got the android
...the ios emulator setup right now to be german but the
program doesn't have any german strings in it so we're going to see what it looks like in german.
And, sorry for the really big emulator today my screen resolution for projecting a strong
...attach so but...so here's a here's app is a chimpanzee
...it shows that shows just some basic...some data and,
but, it gives us pages so we can have different,
different types of ...been shown okay so the key part about swan here is we are in.
...cfour in french.
Source code you see that were not in english but we're still shown...english out because we haven't localized
it has come over and let's checker languages.
So, we're going to go through and we're going to make sure or june
...in french oriented german today.
And, yes, I do...so...emulator.
All right.
So, now we have...set-up and german we had in french still only showed english because that's
all we had so the toolkit is a simple download.
From the microsoft's visual should galleries and I have pre installed here already
so you can see that we have the multiple up toolkit version two-point-zero
technical preview we've been out since october of two thousand twelve but,
this is...version that gives you support for examine projects
...there is a three-one out available that only supports windows and,
we change the architecture so this is definitely the one you want to go with bring
...your environment so that's pre installed already once
that's installed we just go ahead and on the tools menu with our projects selected we
say enable the selected project so I'm going to go ahead enabled the tab
demo the portable class
library holds all the resources for all three platforms so I'm just going to modify that
...I'm going to enable that one enabling the other two in this example wouldn't have any value
or the three wouldn't have any value because they don't hold resources so now
we've been able that just sets the project up so we have the ability to manage
the project in able to work flow so what you'll notice now is when
you write click we have multiple up toolkit menu available on our solution and we
can add languages so let's go ahead and add german.
And, I'm actually just of german the
language not the region the ios is really does the...
does the language not so much the region so this is the best way to do it for that.
And, you'll see that we have a couple of providers here.
So, this is how we give you...services the first one is
the microsoft language portal provider that is all of microsoft professionally
...office windows exchange etc and,
those will come to you for free...will match them up we also have the microsoft
...service and the translator service is are
...translations and it will give you a match that you can see what your software looks like
it does a pretty good job again with any type of recycling or empty you always want
to validate but for most developers...able just to
ship with this and then you can always easily...and I'll show you that to in a little bit so
...german and what you'll notice is an hour project that the multilingual
resources folder appears and...filing here called ted demo
de for german and then fr xcel left and that xcel left file
is a localization industry file format...stands for ex live and,
it has a metadata rich environment in which enables
our workflow so just to show the demo I'm going-to go ahead and
write click this and I'm going to do generate machine translations?
And, what this does the goes off to those to providers I showed on the previous screen ask them to
translate each string independently to give the best result back?
Then you can see here that gave us seven resources back that we
...asked for translations on very limited number of text and the application so
the sounds about right now if we build this really quick we'll see.
We'll see that we have our german dot res x file here was not
there before that's managed by the toolkit you want to leave that one alone because
we make sure the resources synchronized between your source language and all the target
languages if you had fifty target languages...make sure all fifty our current andopens up and show you
that has been translated into those so here's our translations...run this.
Come back over here and hopefully...starts right back up.
And, see that were in german on our emulator.
And, here's our translations so it was that easy to
translate this application once it was localize of all into germany.
Now when you talk about different markets being able to go into, you know,
at least the top ten markets is really critical and with the toolkit we make extremely
easy if you to do it even if you do and cross platform was emerald windows and
ios so you have you have your choice of your targets and this is
their forms its and pretty straightforward let's go ahead that can, you know,
we want maybe want to change these words so we're looking at this...going,
you know, I'm not sure not sure want these translations
...kickback over the project.
And, we'll show you how you take those recycled and emptied
translations and turn them into something a little better for the ones...you don't like so you
...just double-click on the x the file and this launches an external editor and we've made
an external editor to enable your friends and family scenarios and x the file is
supported by pretty much any translation house out there they all know how to handle...because it
is an industry-standard we also provide an editor that supports that
standard so that if you have friends family community translators they're able
to process the file and give a back to you and I'll show...do that just a minute so here's our here's
...german file and you see we have chimpanzee here I'm...go ahead and get a suggestion for this.
So, you see that only the microsoft translator has results
...microsoft apparently hasn't translated
chimpanzee you think we would have but apparently we didn't need to do that so I'm
going-to go ahead and change chimpanzee to the second option
I'll like that one a little better and I'll go ahead and see what else we got here and look at family
and family I want to actually use the one with.
Score the one with the cone was pretty good let's pick this one just because it's from
the language portal common apply the suggestion but I want to protocol
...on the end of it so I can just go in.
I can just go in and post edit this afterwards.
And, I'm go ahead and rebuild run this and we should see that are things have changed.
Yes,...
editor open so it wants to refresh that you can see we have different strings already.
Cohen run this.
And, I'm not going to show it today but this tab app it works exactly the same
for ios for android and for windows phone and they look like they should on
...windows phone like, for example,
on the on the ios app here the tabs at the bottom on android...be at the top
...windows phone...be the...pivot table you see we...scroll between the different columns...I left the
corn off apparently and we did changer...strings but we have
our translations just working within our projects so really is that easy,
you know, like to joke that you give me ten clicks I'll give you ten languages and
it's really true you can get straight into multiple markets
with translation quality of your choosing that easy.
All right so let's go and...down so, you know,...
I'm still not convinced the I want to use those exact words so what I
can do is I can open up this project...can and simply write click it and
go to export translations now this is where I'm
going-to send it to friends and family before we have the toolkit I actually did a program that a translated
into...russian and I had my russian friend translate for me and
well she did really good work...was really painful because at a copy and paste every string
...synchronized I missed a string because when I actually added a new
resource in russian forgot to put in english...gap in my you why almost ship that way with the
toolkit you only do your source language and you let the translation manager
targets so you won't have those type of problems will always synchronize...for you so you see here what we have them
...to...recipient because I...to my friends...and I'm going to set up
...the format because that's the strongest format given intrude standard I can also do
comma delimited some translation houses may prefer that but it gives you the flexibility if they want
to open excel into the translations so we give you that option too and,
it list the files...can export if I...files I could select all of them and send them all at once
...bit...burn for the person...but maybe
...some click okay and this is going to go ahead and bring up a new e-mail my clients.
And, it just puts of real simple email that you can modify you send...going to
...it to it's a translation request there's the attached file.
And, it comes in the information as to where they can download the editor so,
for example.
If I go to this site here.
This will bring up the visual studio gallery site where we have
the technical preview loaded and if I download on this a lot of
people are concerned that I don't have visual studio well it's...msi
...only install the components that are relative to the machine so if I just have a
windows seven box without visual studio because I'm a translator it
will install the editor and the translation services
still get the free microsoft translator and...strings in their projects so
they can do exactly what I do as a developer if I were to do my own translations using the
editor about to two-point-two megabyte download sorts very quick very efficient
...really quick easy way to engage with your friends and family that I know several
developers that just tweet hey I know a few languages I can do these other languages if you
can do my french and spanish I can do your german and russian and they've never have a problem
getting translations and they build a community...developers for support as well so that's
a really great way to do community level translations with it so I'm going to go ahead and
close this off because I'm really not going to sentence someone today.
And, then we're going to pretend that they've actually
...often translated it and they sent back the results so.
...to add a new language to show how that works so let's go ahead and then again I'm just
...language because hey it's time to add franchises good french.
So, I'm going to add french...locale specific on this time.
And, one thing you'll notice is a new provider here when I do the
...specific this is a this is a demo provided we've written by
...that's for tells data...more of a look up roma translation service but because it
knows that my app from english to french is available for it
does display that as of available provider which is interesting point if you
have your own database of translations or you want to use google translator which, you know,
feel for you can pay...service when you get...for free you now have the ability to do a
api...and implement yourself and that's up on our complex site so
it's very easy to do.
So, now I have.
I've my french.
And, I'm going to ahead and do the reverse of what I've just done I'm going to import this?
And, I can say import translations not I didn't
pre machine translate...because I just sent it to a friend they could translate using the
...we talked about earlier but I want to bring in the work that they've done so
...in were no this is out and I'm going to pick the file that they've sent me
we figure out what the files are the naming convention helps but we figure that
out resource enabling if we want to recycle what this will do is
...will loosens some of the...that doesn't have to be the exact resource id
...to be the same source string in the same language pairs this makes
it so you can import translations and...contents from other projects that
...may written, for example, you'll never have to translate the cancel button again and
the french because you probably have it...app and you just you can import that it will take what
...imagine all of norwood account so you're just a great way to go someone import these.
And, scrolls on my list and we'll see that we have seven resources have been imported so
these are importers that are now...frenchie open...this file.
Will see that these are translations available to us for french and
again...my friend is translated they've marked...translated
they sent back to me and of course here's our...provider showing because it's now the first provider?
All right so that's how easy to this so,
you saw that for me to do german simply just said enable
...german machine translate
...for me to do french which I wanted to have a friend of the translations for
...simply just
...french export...and run and now...semi
emulator up so that's the core of the localization workflow that we give you for free with
multiple up toolkit again all the translation services that we provider free you can
extend...your own set and now you can enter many markets with little work
again focusing on your applications functionality alertness target the languages.
So, that's the salmon forms.
We're going-to go ahead and switch over and we're going to look at the
ios version of this ...also supports ios projects
that use iowa's based uri but common portable
class library code behind this is great for if you're writing a service to connect
to as you're doing anything that is common and there's about sixty percent reduces what
is what they advertise for that and I found that to be fairly true again,
with forms I got more like ninety five percent because it was commons animal but you also want to be able
to picture existing ios apps take ui copying...eml environment do
...csharp so let's go ahead and jump over and do one of those?
Some come back to my project and open up a new one.
So, we have a
touch ios again as a saying I'm pulling all these from the get hub environment
...your exam room evolve twenty fourteen they have a
bunch of examples on how to...amr in the different technologies so I've just
pull this one down I need to localize it so I made it localize of all the way you make
a and ios app local as well brief overview of it as you create your
...language code.
Dot l proj and then put a strings file and I call mine localization localize
...that strings so here all the gestures from this is a gesture app
...I've made these look liable I wrote a quick little ext just
...goes up so that...when we look at the code the code just has
just cheated and I just say the original hard...string they've put in
dot the extensions...pull...with ios of it doesn't
find resource it gives you back whatever string you ask for so they recommend that you use the
string you'd want to be displayed that...fallback is always something that's readable instead of a resource
id that you may not want to show...enough about the little primer on android
the or ios localization so again as you saw before all we
used to...toolkit.
Emulator...german still so I'm going-to go ahead do german again.
Again, I've got my to translation providers.
Created the dl proj.
Created the multi-lingual resources
same as before we do the exif we manager target resources for you.
And, I just generators machine translations and now I'm getting my ios
app from the...examples into german.
Just with a few clicks.
So, let's go ahead and run this.
Now we're going to run in german.
Here's...german strings.
So, you see it was that easy I literally just
...these languages give-me some machine translation and now have
an ios app for the german market I may want to tuned so
my string links german can be pretty big again we
...make sure we size it but now I have now I
have my different things here's one of those things you really want to watch for the drag me these
are images with hard coded text we'll talk about that little bit but that's...you can see
how that's a problem but I do have a fully localized german app for a ios.
All right let's go ahead and do the same thing for android
some you're probably saying well that's really cool but I use salmon studio online
...for a develop a lot I do
...visual studios weller bounce back and forth between the two but how do I
...to take advantage of that...let me show you here with the visual studio
...support we give you the workflow but we don't break you when you move back to
the salmon environment so I'm going-to go ahead and take this application here and we're
...jump right into it I'm going to pretend like I'm not doing a video and just localized myself?
So, I've been able to it...ahead and add my languages.
That's...both german and french...time because...
So, there's my french german.
Click here.
And, you'll see the project is going to be expanded off to have again
the multilingual resources folder with rx the files in it...can
...the target files for our resources that have
our values dot language code that's where...android works so we just
mapped image to so again here's our multilingual resources here's our
...propagating pretty...of see in this pattern by now which is the point
windows ios android solve the same workflow for-you.
And, down here we generate your strings files for
your particular locales and that's the secret as to why we work in your environment's so I'm going
to go ahead just write click here and I'm a translate both of these are the same time
someone generate machine translations and you see that since we
...to we give dialogue that shows two of them...at the same time
...a...how want to do my build in visual studio because visual stewed in the build
...were removed from our x the file to the native target resource file
so-if you don't build those files will actually be empty and you'll be gone watts will
store for me, yeah, but, you gotta make sure you do the last step.
So, we're doing a quick build.
And, that's going to synchronize are files so that are language files will be
...was building I'm...to come over here and, startup.
...studio and kill off...
Okay, so, do have a successful build and...french during files in this is
a very limited string resource files just a quick demo for a quick button
you can see that we have our native resources for android in french
and same pro-german ok so if I come over to
...studio and I open up the layout project?
Okay, so, you see here that we've...the project up
...to this is the layout again from the cameron get up site
for demos and as we saw we added...visual studio and we have languages
populated we have our french language here so I've got the emulator up
...so we're going-to go ahead and just run this environment studio...that
...build breaks and that it actually does create
...french project so it's a pretty simple program is just a button click and
here's french if I were to switch my emulator to german since we didn't
...german with the initial language selection I would also have german so now I have a very quick
demo...from simon's website that shows english french and
german which just a few clicks inside...visual studio but then transports overtures
...studio so you continue use...studio if that your id of choice because
our pros and cons to both so now that's a very nice partnership...nice mixture of
...able to do so again a quick recap is that we have the
ability to show you how to...forms how-to-do-it
...ios native ui apps and how to use eminent android native...
apps with the toolkit again...all the translation services for
free and you can extend those to yourself all right so let's go back to our slides and
...look...them also some of the questions
...constantly asked...dark about the toolkit
...globalization and generalization and general is...globalization
...general is what are the things I need to worry about
...truthfully it's a pretty small list I mean you can get really deep and, you know,
like microsoft has intense processes that we do for localization globalization
process but...really if you just do the top few you solve most
...your problems so make sure that your market aware
rate uone make sure that you don't use custom calendar controls
not every country starts on sunday not every day for the first
...not of a country uses a goring calendar so you want to make sure the
calendar controls are location aware so you want your
french calendars I believe they start on monday you want your you want you counters to be correct
...you want to know that the type of...those can be displayed if you spend all of your time
coding that when the system can give it to for free you're not making features that make
your application stand out in the marketplace so definitely focus on using the api
...that are there are classic examples...time some code I've seen and used to
do myself is string format zero one two months
...here right definitely avoid that barely works in the us
...do military time for us military so you want to stay
away from that start building application globalization by default I've worked with
a several individuals and,...so what was it like to use the toolkit for the first-time and said actually
...pretty easy it just took us two weeks to make the software of available to be able to have
...localization because we didn't build into start so we had...the entire
...team and make them focused on
...and localization injection if you do globalization localization up-front it
becomes a habit just like writing good code becomes a habit and now if you want to add a
language it really is a matter of targeting the market you want and now you can get into many
markets expand your global reach and,
be able to service more customers with very little effort especially if...the toolkit?
Design layouts make sure that when you do design layout that
...not cramming everything together especially in the mobile...you know,
if you have an iphone to an...android phone to...tablet
...phone all the way it to windows desktop now with you ap you
...make sure your controls are aligns so that they flow naturally with the
lay-out of the particular form factor if you pushing together thinking english-only
it's not going to look good in russian...german which are some key markets.
Localization best practices and
...pretty straightforward but all of your translate...strings or localize
...strings into a resource file you don't want to put them in
hard coded because then you have to go back and fix it and you'd rather...the
fix right so that's a great way just to make a practice of doing that for ios it is,
you know, language code dot l proj and for android it is
values underscore language code underscore...region again the toolkit
multiple got toolkit will...that for...so you have to worry about it just make your source language the
when you want and we'll go to the rest if you start with german will
...english so feel free to go from one language to
any other language that you want and we'll...there...again we talked about the lay-out of
the ui forty percent growth is what you're going to see in all languages you
saw on some of the earlier demos when I do too german it barely fit on the
...screen because the translation was correct for that string but it's of more for pulse
...the number of space that...you want to be able to work the...or make sure you
...work in that space do hard code strings that you don't want to localize,
you know, maybe...maybe your product name as...me want to key standard you don't want to
have a localized maybe you do make the decision don't put in a resource file if you
don't want localized because you that will just be instructions to a translator or even
...tools so please leave us alone that's just more work avoid text images you saw in the
iowa's demoted the buttons were actually hard code with text so,
I couldn't localize them I would actually
have to pay myself take time to take the strings out and then overlay
in the code or to have a translator give me a layered file with multipleimages
with multiple translations and dashes cost so you can avoid cost end-time just by
overlaying your text on top of an image rather than embedding the man and then, you know,
obviously avoid concatenate strings spanish is a classic language were the verb
noun orders switched a lot if you have hard coded in your thing string format
brackets zero bracket one...can't fix that if you put the records or
...one in your file you can put a note saying hey, you know,
for spanish this zero means this and this one means this and they will know whether
...which are not...application will look better and feel more like
the native language which is your ultimate go right so user parameterized placeholder rather than
hard-core in a concatenate these are some pretty basic practices but a lot of people don't do if
you do these you can discover becomes natural and your apps just work?
Okay, so,...some resources for...
Resources obviously we're talking about the multi-lingual up toolkit today so version
...when you want for the cross platform...truthfully the when you want for windows support as well it's...go
forward model so here's a link for a quick download on that we have a blog that we do so
...talks about
...releases and we have other information we post up there and we have a
user foresight which we listen to intensely go-to our user versailles intel's what you like
...but like...a bug let us know...get fixed hopefully.
And, we'll just continue to work with you on these areas our goal is to make use
successful and reaching as many markets as your product needs to go into and we're here to help you
with that translation resources you saw that we provided to vendors the or providers in
our system so we have the microsoft translator that's a pay for service
but if you want to do it in a website to dynamic translations it's a really great way to go
they give you think it's two million translations...characters fields how the
count words maybe for free which is pretty sufficient for
most people but if you need more you can go into that never everybody's used being translator versus
...name for tool translate a website works pretty well and,
then of course all of microsoft professionally...strings are on the language portal site and there's
a link to it you can get the strings interactively or you can actually hook up the same api as we do.
Thank you very much for listen the session on how to localize for
cross platform using the multilingual up toolkit
...and visual studio environment is a great environment
...the...up toolkit on top of it and now you have multiple market multiple
platforms support at your fingertips thank you.